Jacob Liberman

jacobliberman@gmail.com +1 (512) 632-0098 Austin, TX

Summary

Product manager with the ability to context switch between C-level strategic planning and engineering level technical discussion. Background in open source software, cloud computing, and high performance computing (HPC). Extensive experience working with the US government and in LATAM. Multiple industry and academic publications. Frequent presenter at technology conferences.

Related Experience

Senior Principal Product Manager, Emerging Technology

Red Hat, May 2018 - Present

 Field product manager with cross organizational, cross product impact. Developed OpenShift on OpenStack reference architecture. Developed and delivered hands-on OpenShift 4 training to Red Hat SAs. Assisted strategic aerospace customer with GPU adoption and kubeflow POC in cloud environment. Led OpenShift on OpenStack hackfest, first cross-product engineering and field enablement exercise at Red Hat.

Principal Product Manager, Cloud, Virtualization, Containers

Red Hat, November 2016 - May 2018

 Conducted customer interviews and discovery sessions to gather product feedback and prioritize roadmap feature requests. Assisted strategic customers with private cloud planning and implementation for NFV, HPC, and enterprise use cases. Planned and executed several OpenStack hackfests for field enablement and product improvement. Co-presented OpenStack Summit session with Oak Ridge National Lab.

Principal Software Engineer, Cloud Computing

Red Hat, January 2012 - November 2016

• Developed, tested, and published cloud computing reference architectures based on Red Hat OpenStack Platform, Enterprise Linux, and Cloudera and HortonWorks Hadoop. Contributed code and patches to upstream OpenStack Rally project.

Performance Engineer, Scientific and Cloud Computing

Advanced Micro Devices, November 2009 – January 2012

Designed and conducted server performance studies for competitive analysis. Helped customers
improve the performance of their codes on our systems. Managed lab clusters for remote
customer evaluation. Traveled to customer sites to conduct benchmarks for acceptance testing.
Ran standard HPC benchmarks such as SPEC MPI and SPEC OMP.

Development Engineer, High Performance Computing

Dell, August 2006 – November 2009

• Lead performance engineer. Conducted server performance studies using standard benchmarks and applications. Shared results via publications and presentations. Evaluated storage, networking, and software technologies for inclusion in our product. Ran HPL for top 500 submissions. Developed predictive server performance model for CERN Atlas experiment.

Education

Texas State University

Master's Program, Computer Science (in progress)

- Researching computational model of human eye movement. Optimizing parallel multidimensional search algorithm for CUDA.

The University of Texas at Austin

Master's Degree, Technology in Education

- 4.0 GPA with course work in learning theory, statistics, and scientific computing.

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor's Degree, English - Creative writing

Service

Board Member — Texas Rugby Alumni Network

Texas Exes, May 2015 - Present

Board member

Trojans Pop Warner Football, *August 2015 – 2017*

Rugby 7s Head Coach

University of Texas at Austin, August 2010 - July 2015

- Ranked #12 in 2013 out of more than 500 college rugby programs.

Performance analyst

Philippine Rugby Football Union, June 2013 – August 2013

- Scouting and video analysis during the 2013 Rugby 7s World Cup in Moscow, Russia.

Awards

- Red Hat Portfolio Marketing 2018 Customer Impact Award
- Red Hat Summit 2017 Best Presenter award
- Red Hat Summit 2016 Best Presenter award

Selected Publications

https://github.com/jliberma/publications